<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Science on Let&#39;s See What Happens When We Take Away The Puppy</title>
    <link>/oliverclark.github.io/./tags/open-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Science on Let&#39;s See What Happens When We Take Away The Puppy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/oliverclark.github.io/./tags/open-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Drawing A Line in the Randomness: General Linear Models and Simulations</title>
      <link>/oliverclark.github.io/./2018/06/20/drawing-a-line-in-the-randomness-general-linear-models-and-simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/oliverclark.github.io/./2018/06/20/drawing-a-line-in-the-randomness-general-linear-models-and-simulations/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Chosing parameters General Linear Model Reverse Engineering Running Analyses (Welch’s t Test) Analysis (ANOVA) Power Analysis Brute Force Power Analysis   Introduction I am currently planning a replication and extension of an experimental study that had a count-based dependent variable. The aim is to submit it as a registered report before collecting the data and so I need to have an analysis plan and estimated sample size/stopping rule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pre-Registration</title>
      <link>/oliverclark.github.io/./2017/11/02/pre-registration-rmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/oliverclark.github.io/./2017/11/02/pre-registration-rmd/</guid>
      <description>Last night I submitted my first pre-registration to the OSF.io Pre-registration challenge.
The study is a Bayesian meta-analysis of studies using video game avatars to influence health behaviours and attitudes. The process involved the following:
Deconstructing a previous meta-analysis Initially I wanted to learn meta-analytical methods by using previous data rather than beating my own data into submission. This was a difficult process since:
 the supplementary data was a pdf with that weird tendancy to select content in random patterns</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>